Claudia S Everett Software Engineer

Email: claudiaeverett9@gmail.com

**Phone:** (540) 497-4197

Clearance: Secret Clearance Residence: Roanoke, Virginia Willing to relocate: Yes % Willing to Travel: 20%

## **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

I have 2 years and a half of experience in software development, design, testing in full-scale applications to create unique user experience from conception to implementation using ReactJS and NodeJS. I work on SharePoint platform and front-end technologies such as Angular 4, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS assisting NASA HPD team implementing their collaborative portal. For the past 1 year, I gained experience building bots using Twilio and cloud data migration with AWS.

## **EDUCATION**

BS Information Technology at Pennsylvania State University in 2019 BS Business at Southern New Hampshire University in 2013

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Full Stack Developer Certificate from freeCodeCamps (2019)
- The Complete Web Development: Zero to Mastery on Udemy (2018)
- MCSA Web Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 (2020)
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect (expected exam date August 2020)

# **SUMMARY OF SKILLS, TOOLS, AND TECHNOLOGIES:**

Technologies: Microsoft SharePoint 2013, VB.NET, Twilio, AWS CloudWatch, EC2.

Programming Languages/Frameworks: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, ReactJS, AngularJS and 4, NodeJS,

MongoDB, SQL, OOP, Java, and Ruby.

Development/Testing Tools: Visual Studio, GitHub, Bitbucket, NetBeans, VSCode, JIRA, Eclipse, Sublime

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:**

# Booz Allen Hamilton, Software Engineer NASA

September 2019 – Present

- Develop collaborative SharePoint application for Nasa Heliophysics team built in SharePoint.
- Test, maintain, and recommend software improvements to ensure strong functionality and optimization.
- Collaborate with product team members to implement new features.
- Work with experience team members to conduct root cause analysis of issues, review new and existing code and perform unit testing.

## **Vision Point Systems, Software Engineer**

**April 2018 – August 2019** 

- Performed maintenance on the EC2 instances that control the functionality of start and stop of servers through Lambda.
- Worked in web application using IVR tool Twilio and NodeJS to support the client 911 emergency system.
- Assisted with software development progress by Scrum, using Jira to track issues and manage tasks.
- Managed Bitbucket repositories and permissions, including branching, tagging and collaborating

with other team members.

- Leveraged knowledge in **Twilio**, **JavaScript**, debug using **Chrome Developer tools**, and EC2.
- Responsible for front-end development using ReactJS/Angular 7 and backend using Node JS, Express JS, MongoDB, the complete MERN Stack to provide RESTful API.

# Freelance, Web Developer/Software Developer

December 2017 to June 2018

- Utilized a wide variety of front-end tools (HTML/CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS) to create UI design.
- Developed and updated a web page quickly and effectively using HTML5, CSS3, Java Script,
   jQuery and Angular4 with the webpage crosses browser, desktop and mobile compatibility.
- Utilized agile software lifecycle methodologies using daily scrums and JIRA to track project.
- Tested and maintained website to ensure functionality.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Project-Name: Robofriends**

https://claudiabringaseverett.github.io/robofriends/

Built with **ReactJS** and **Robot** API, this application utilizes was built to search for robot friends. Robofriends displays cards with name and email for each robot and a search finder to easily find a friend. The site is fully responsive, and it was styled using Tychons and deployed with GitHub pages.

# **Project-Name: Weather App**

https://claudiabringaseverett.github.io/weather-app/

This weather application was built using ReactJS and weather API to find the temperature anywhere in the world. Styled in Bootstrap and deployed with GitHub pages.

#### **Project-Name: Coffee Order**

Currently building a chatbot using **Twilio**, and **NodeJS+ ExpressJS** to order coffee through text message. Interaction created on Twilio console, studio flow and autopilot to generate smart response to users.

#### **VOLUNTEERISM & LEADERSHIP**

# **Facebook Developer Circle, Participant**

July 2019 – Present

Attend meetups with other developers or aspiring developers and we share our experiences and skills. We work on weekly labs and we get together to share our progress. Curriculum facilitated by Developer Team.

## **PAX, Community Coordinator**

Jun 2017 - Present

Establish and maintain relationships with local public high schools
Recruit and screen local families to host international exchange students
Supervise exchange students throughout their stay to ensure students safety and well-being
Check-in with students monthly by phone or in-person and submit reports of their status and experience.

#### **OTHER**

I speak Spanish fluently; arts and hiking are a must.